Amos Pinchot Papers
Manuscript Division, Library of Congress
Amos Pinchot Papers 1856-1945 1909-1942
MSS36251
Pinchot, Amos, 1873-1944
50,000 items
170 containers plus 12 oversize
73 linear feet
Manuscript Division, Library of Congress Washington, D.C.
Lawyer and publicist. Correspondence, memoranda, diaries, notebooks, printed articles, speeches, newspaper clippings, scrapbooks, and other printed material reflecting Pinchot's interests in civil liberties, labor problems, government, and politics.
Selected Search Terms
The following terms have been used to index the description of this collection in the LC Catalog. They are grouped by name of person or organization, by subject or location, and by occupation and listed alphabetically.
People
Borah, William Edgar, 1865-1940--Correspondence.; Bryant, Louise, 1885-1936--Correspondence.; Garfield, James Rudolph, 1865-1950--Correspondence.; Ickes, Harold L. (Harold LeClair), 1874-1952--Correspondence.; Kent, William, 1864-1928--Correspondence.; Kingsbury, John Adams, 1876-1956--Correspondence.; La Guardia, Fiorello H. (Fiorello Henry), 1882-1947--Correspondence.; Lewis, John L. (John Llewellyn), 1880-1969--Correspondence.; Pinchot family.; Pinchot, Amos, 1873-1944.; Pinchot, Gifford, 1865-1946--Correspondence.; Pound, Ezra, 1885-1972--Correspondence.; Reed, John, 1887-1920--Correspondence.; Roosevelt, Franklin D. (Franklin Delano), 1882-1945--Correspondence.; Roosevelt, Theodore, 1858-1919--Correspondence.; Stimson, Henry L. (Henry Lewis), 1867-1950--Correspondence.
Organizations
America First Committee.; League of Nations.; Progressive Party (U.S.: 1912); United States. National Industrial Recovery Act of 1933.; United States. Sherman Act.; United States. Supreme Court.
Subjects
Antitrust law--United States.; Civil rights.; Elections--United States--History--20th century.; Housing, Cooperative.; Labor disputes.; Labor.; Militarism.; New Deal, 1933-1939.; Petroleum industry and trade.; Political science.; Politics, Practical.; Railroads.; Treaties.; War.
Places
United States--Economic policy--1933-1945.; United States--Politics and government--20th century.
Occupations
Lawyers.; Publicists.
Acquisition Information
The papers of Amos Pinchot, lawyer and publicist, were given to the Library of Congress by his wife, Ruth Pickering Pinchot, 1944-1953. Additional material was given by Mark Meyer in 1985.
Transfers
Some photographs have been transferred to the Library's Prints and Photographs Division where they are identified as part of these papers.
Access and Restrictions
The papers of Amos Pinchot are open to research. Researchers are advised to contact the Manuscript Reading Room prior to visiting. Many collections are stored off-site and advance notice is needed to retrieve these items for research use.
Biographical Note
Date Event
1873 Born, Paris, France
1897 B.A., Yale University, New Haven, Conn.
circa 1898 Studied law, Columbia University, New York, N.Y.
1898 Served in First New York Volunteer Cavalry in Puerto Rico during the Spanish-American War
circa 1899 Studied law, New York Law School, New York, N.Y.
1900 1901 Deputy assistant district attorney, New York County, N.Y.
1912 Supported Theodore Roosevelt and the Progressive Party
1914 1916 Active in movement to keep United States out World War I
1919 1920 Organizer, Committee of 48 Trustee, New York Philharmonic Society, New York, N.Y. Founder and member, executive committee, Civil Liberties Union
1932 Supported Franklin D. Roosevelt for president
1935 Broke with policies of President Franklin D. Roosevelt and the New Deal
1939 1941 Opposed United States entry into World War II Member, executive committee, New York chapter of America First Committee
1944 Died, New York, N.Y.
Scope and Content Note
The papers of Amos Pinchot (1873-1944) span the years 1856-1945, with the bulk of the collection dating from 1909 to 1942. The collection chiefly reflects Pinchot's career as a lawyer and reformer and consists of six series: Family Correspondence, General Correspondence, Subject File, Speeches and Writings, Printed Matter, and Oversize.
Topics of importance in the papers include civil liberties, labor problems, the Sherman Antitrust Act, opposition to militarism and war, the League of Nations, the Progressive Party, oil scandals, government ownership of railroads, the National Industrial Recovery Act and New Deal legislation, reorganization of the Supreme Court, cooperative housing, America First Committee, and presidential campaigns from 1916 to 1940. Prominent correspondents include William Edgar Borah, Louise Bryant, James Rudolph Garfield, Harold L. Ickes, William Kent, John Adams Kingsbury, Fiorello H. La Guardia, John L. Lewis, Gifford Pinchot, Ezra Pound, John Reed (1887-1920), Franklin D. Roosevelt, Theodore Roosevelt (1858-1919), and Henry L. Stimson.
Arrangement of the Papers
The collection is arranged in six series:
Family Correspondence, 1863-1941
General Correspondence, 1857-1942
Subject File, 1856-1944
Speeches and Writings, 1897-1944
Printed Matter, 1910-1945
Oversize, 1916-1941
Container List
- Family Correspondence, 1863-1941 (Box 1-3)
  Letters sent and received by Amos Pinchot and Pinchot family members.
  Arranged chronologically by year and month.
  - 1863, 1879-1910, (9 folders) (Box 1)
  - 1911-1913, 1919-1925, (7 folders) (Box 2)
  - 1926-1941, (3 folders) (Box 3)
  - Undated, (3 folders)
- General Correspondence, 1857-1942 (Box 4-70)
  Letters sent and received.
  Organized into a chronological file and special file. The chronological file is arranged by year and month. The special file is arranged alphabetically by name of person, organization, or topic.
  - Chronological file (Box 4)
    - circa 1879, 1898-1908
    - 1909, (2 folders)
    - 1910
      - Jan.-Oct., 1910; (3 folders)
      - Nov.-Dec. (Box 5)
    - 1911
      - Jan.-Oct., (6 folders)
      - Nov.-Dec., (3 folders) (Box 6)
    - 1912
      - Jan.-Apr., (4 folders)
      - May-Nov., (7 folders) (Box 7)
      - Dec. (Box 8)
    - 1913
      - Jan.-Apr., (4 folders)
      - May-Oct., (7 folders) (Box 9)
      - Nov.-Dec., (2 folders) (Box 10)
    - 1914
      - Jan.-Mar., (3 folders)
      - Apr., (1 folder) (Box 11)
      - May-Sept., (5 folders)
      - Oct.-Dec., (4 folders) (Box 12)
    - 1915
      - Jan., (2 folders)
      - Feb., (1 folder) (Box 13)
      - Mar.-June, (6 folders)
      - July-Nov., (7 folders) (Box 14)
      - Dec. (Box 15)
    - 1916
      - Jan.-Mar., (4 folders)
      - Apr.-July, (7 folders) (Box 16)
      - Aug.-Nov., (7 folders) (Box 17)
      - Dec., (2 folders) (Box 18)
    - 1917
      - Jan.-Feb., (6 folders)
      - Mar., (3 folders) (Box 19)
      - Apr., (2 folders); (6 folders); (5 folders) (Box 20, Box 21)
      - May, (1 folder); (6 folders) (Box 22)
      - June-July, (6 folders) (Box 23)
      - Aug., (1 folder) (Box 24)
      - Sept., (3 folders)
      - Oct., (3 folders); (4 folders) (Box 25)
      - Nov., (3 folders); (1 folders) (Box 26)
      - Dec., (2 folders)
    - 1918
      - Jan., (2 folders)
      - Feb.-June, (7 folders) (Box 27)
      - July-Nov., (6 folders) (Box 28)
      - Dec., (1 folder); (2 folders) (Box 29)
    - 1919
      - Jan.-Apr., (4 folders)
      - May-Nov., (7 folders) (Box 30)
      - Dec. (Box 31)
    - 1920
      - Jan.-May, (5 folders)
      - June-Nov., (6 folders) (Box 32)
      - Dec. (Box 33)
    - 1921
      - Jan.-Nov., (6 folders)
      - Dec. (Box 34)
    - 1922, (6 folders)
    - 1923 (Box 35)
      - Jan.-Aug., (7 folders)
      - Sept.-Dec., (3 folders) (Box 36)
    - 1924
      - Jan.-Mar., (3 folders)
      - Apr.-Dec., (6 folders) (Box 37)
    - 1925, (6 folders) (Box 38)
    - 1926, (4 folders) (Box 39)
    - 1927
      - Jan.-Mar., (3 folders)
      - Apr.-Dec., (4 folders) (Box 40)
    - 1928
      - Jan.-Apr., (2 folders)
      - May-Dec., (3 folders) (Box 41)
    - 1929, (3 folders)
    - 1930, (4 folders) (Box 42)
    - 1931
      - Jan.-May, (2 folders)
      - June-Dec., (3 folders) (Box 43)
    - 1932
      - Jan.-May, (4 folders)
      - June-Dec., (4 folders) (Box 44)
    - 1933
      - Jan.-Mar., (2 folders)
      - Apr.-Dec., (6 folders) (Box 45)
    - 1934
      - Jan.
      - Feb.-Dec., (7 folders) (Box 46)
    - 1935 (Box 47)
      - Jan.-Apr., (6 folders)
      - May-Aug., (6 folders) (Box 48)
      - Sept.-Dec., (3 folders) (Box 49)
    - 1936
      - Jan.-May, (5 folders)
      - June-Dec., (8 folders) (Box 50)
    - 1937 (Box 51)
      - Jan.-Apr., (6 folders)
      - May-June, (4 folders) (Box 52)
      - July, (1 folder) (Box 53)
      - Aug.-Sept., (4 folders)
      - Oct.-Dec., (4 folders) (Box 54)
    - 1938
      - Jan., (2 folders); (1 folder) (Box 55)
      - Feb.-Apr., (8 folders)
      - May, (1 folder); (3 folders) (Box 56)
      - June-Aug., (5 folders)
      - Sept., (1 folder); (3 folders) (Box 57)
      - Oct.-Dec., (5 folders)
    - 1939
      - Jan., (1 folder) (Box 58)
      - Feb.-Sept., (10 folders)
      - Oct.-Dec., (4 folders) (Box 59)
    - 1940
      - Jan.-Apr., (4 folders)
      - May-Sept., (7 folders) (Box 60)
      - Oct., (2 folders); (1 folder) (Box 61)
      - Nov.-Dec., (2 folders)
    - 1941
      - Jan.-Mar., (5 folders)
      - Apr.-June, (6 folders) (Box 62)
      - July, (1 folder) (Box 63)
      - Aug.-Oct., (5 folders)
      - Nov.-Dec., (5 folders) (Box 64)
    - 1942, (4 folders)
    - Undated, (6 folders); (3 folders) (Box 65, Box 66, Box 67)
  - Special file
    - Bryant, Louise, and John Reed (1887-1920), 1916-1917, undated
    - Commission on Industrial Relations, undated
    - Craig, Charles L., 1923
    - Filene, E. A., 1923
    - Lippman, Walter, articles and correspondence about, 1933
    - Miscellany
      - 1923-1930
      - 1931-1942, (6 folders) (Box 68)
      - Undated, (2 folders); (1 folder) (Box 69)
    - National Popular Government League, printed matter, 1929-1935, (3 folders)
    - “Political party platforms,” printed matter, 1857
    - Pound, Ezra, 1935-1939, undated
    - Progressive Party, National Committee
      - 1914
        - Jan.-June, (3 folders)
        - July-Dec. (Box 70)
      - 1919-1920
      - Undated
    - Reed, John (1887-1920) See Container 67, Bryant, Louise, and John Reed
- Subject File, 1856-1944 (Box 71-132)
  Memoranda, notes, reports, printed matter, and other material.
  Arranged alphabetically by topic.
  - America First Committee, 1941, (7 folders); (4 folders) (Box 71, Box 72)
  - American Committee Against Militarism, 1916-1922, (1 folder); (5 folders) (Box 73)
  - American Committee on War Finance, 1912-1927 See also Oversize, (3 folders); (4 folders); (2 folders); (1 folder) (Box 74, Box 75, Box 76, Box 77, Box 78)
  - American history, 1885, undated
  - Ballinger, Richard, A. case, 1908-1911, 1927, (5 folders); (6 folders); (4 folders) (Box 79, Box 80, Box 81, Box 82)
  - Banking bill, 1935, (2 folders) (Box 83)
  - Bolshevism, 1920
  - Bonus Expeditionary Force, 1932
  - Boone and Crockett Club, 1917-1922
  - Borah, William Edgar, speech, Apr. 30, 1936
  - Campaign material
    - Hilquit, Morris, 1917
    - Presidential (Box 84)
      - 1928, (3 folders)
      - 1936, (7 folders)
      - 1940, (4 folders) (Box 85)
  - Censorship, 1931
  - Civil Liberties Union, 1917-1920, (1 folder) (Box 86)
  - Coal, 1923 For additional information see Container 137, “Why People Freeze”, (2 folders)
  - Committee of 48, circa 1919-1920, (5 folders); (1 folder) (Box 87, Box 88)
  - Committee on Democratic Control, 1917
  - Communist riot, 1930
  - Conscription, 1916-1919, (3 folders); (1 folder) (Box 89)
  - Co-operative Housing and Garden City League of America, 1920-1921
  - Defense, 1914-1926, (3 folders)
  - Education, 1925-circa 1928 For additional information see Container 132, Young, Owen D., (2 folders) (Box 90)
  - Equality, 1914
  - Executive Reorganization Bill, 1937
  - Florida peonage, 1923
  - Foreign trade, 1941
  - Freedom of discussion, undated
  - Free speech, 1915-1919, (1 folder); (2 folders) (Box 91)
  - German indemnity, 1917-1921, (3 folders)
  - Gholston, J. G., reference letter on, 1919, undated (Box 92)
  - Government and business, by Russell Davenport, 1939
  - Government ownership, 1910-1928, (3 folders); (1 folder) (Box 93)
  - Hoover, Herbert, and power See Container 109, Power
  - Individualism, 1921-1923
  - Industrial Relations Committee, 1915-1917, (2 folders)
  - Ireland, 1920-1921 (Box 94)
  - King Trust See Container 131, War and the King Trust
  - Labor, 1914-1921, (4 folders); (3 folders) (Box 95)
  - Laski, Harold J., 1941
  - Law, state, undated
  - League of Nations, 1918-1920, (2 folders)
  - Liberal Group, 1922-1924 (Box 96)
  - Liberalism, 1919-1923, 1937-1939
  - Lindbergh, Charles A., war statement, 29 Mar. 1941
  - Masses, 1913-1918, (4 folders)
  - Mexico, 1911-1921, 1927, (3 folders) (Box 97)
  - Miscellany, 1856, 1895, 1904-1931, undated, (1 folder); (6 folders); (5 folders); (4 folders) (Box 98, Box 99, Box 100, Box 101, Box 102)
  - Miscellany, 1856, 1895, 1904-1931, undated, (2 folders) (Box 103)
  - Money, 1923, 1933-1938, (1 folder); (5 folders) (Box 104)
  - Monopoly, 1913-1915 For additional information see Containers 97-103, Miscellany (Box 105)
  - National Electric Light Association, 1925-1931, 1941
  - Naval Armament Conference, London, England, 1930
  - Neutrality Act, repeal of, 1940-1941
  - Oil, circa 1924-1929 (Box 106)
  - Oil and steel, 1908-1910, 1923-1930, (8 folders)
  - Patriotism, undated
  - Peace or armed force, 1918-1920 (Box 107)
  - People's Council of America, 1916-1918
  - People's League for Economic Security, undated
  - Photographs, undated
  - Pinchot, Gifford, candidacy for Senate in 1914
  - Plumb Plan League, 1919-1920, (2 folders)
  - Political, 1936-1938 (Box 108)
  - Popular government, 1907-circa 1911, (1 folder); (2 folders) (Box 109)
  - Power, 1927-1931, (5 folders)
  - “The Presidency,” 1929 (Box 110)
  - Progressive Party, 1909-1924, (2 folders); (6 folders); (7 folders) (Box 111, Box 112, Box 113)
  - Prohibition, 1929-1932 (Box 114)
  - Quinlan, Patrick, case, 1913-1915
  - Raifuku Maru (Japanese freighter), Apr. 21, 1925
  - Railroads and Interstate Commerce Commission
    - Government ownership, 1911-1915
    - Reports, 1923-1928, (2 folders); (4 folders) (Box 115, Box 116, Box 117)
    - Speeches given in Canadian House of Commons, 1931-1934 (Box 118)
    - Miscellaneous, 1910-1912
  - Reciprocity with Canada, 1910-1912
  - Reconstruction, 1927
  - Record, George L., notes for, 1916-1933, (3 folders); (5 folders); (6 folders) (Box 119, Box 120, Box 121)
  - Reforestation, regarding proposed amendment, 1931
  - Religion, undated
  - Rockefeller Foundation, Colorado, 1913-1916, (3 folders)
  - Roosevelt, Theodore (1858-1919), 1908-1912, 1926-1931, 1941, (2 folders) (Box 122)
  - Root, Elihu, 1910-1916
  - Russia, 1918-1921
  - Secret treaties, 1917-1921, 1932, (2 folders) (Box 123)
  - Sherman Antitrust Act, 1911-1914, 1927-1930, (2 folders)
  - Standard Oil Co., 1888, 1911-1912, 1923-1934, (4 folders); (3 folders) (Box 124)
  - State law See Container 95, Law, state
  - Steel, 1912-1933 For additional information see Container 106, Oil and steel; Container 128, United States Steel, (5 folders); (1 folder) (Box 125)
  - Stimson, Henry L., memorandum, unpublished, 1932-1934
  - Sub-Committee of the Committee of ’76, 1933-1934
  - Supreme Court decisions, bill for the reorganization of, 1937, (4 folders)
  - Tax, land, 1908-1917, (6 folders) (Box 126)
  - Titanic disaster, 1912-1913 (Box 127)
  - Trust See Container 131, War and the King Trust
  - Unemployment, 1914-1916, 1930-1934, (5 folders)
  - United States Steel, 1904, 1912-1921, (5 folders) (Box 128)
  - War, 1902-1904, 1914-1921, (2 folders); (6 folders) (Box 129, Box 130)
  - War and the King Trust, 1916-1917 (Box 131)
  - War hysteria, 1917
  - Waste, 1941-1942, (2 folders)
  - Water power, circa 1927-1929, (1 folder) (Box 132)
  - Whalen, Grover A., case, 1930
  - Wilson, Woodrow, 1913-1914
  - World War I, newspaper clippings, 1917-1918, (2 folders)
  - Young, Owen D., and education, 1928-1931, (2 folders)
- Speeches and Writings, 1897-1944 (Box 133-152)
  Drafts and printed versions of articles, addresses, speeches, and other writings, and related letters, notes and notebooks.
  Arranged alphabetically by type of material.
  - Drafts and related matter (Box 133)
    - Addresses
      - “The American Liberal and the Liberal Program,” Dec., 1932
      - Civil liberties, 1933
      - Philadelphia, Pa., civil liberties speech, Mar., 1933
      - “Should We Have a Central Bank?” Jan. 6, 1935
      - Balancing the budget, Jan., 1936
      - Executive League of America, Jan. 21, 1936
      - Landon, Alfred M., presidential candidacy, Oct., 1936
      - New York Board of Trade, Dec., 8, 1937
      - Untitled, Dec., 1937
      - America's Town Meeting of the Air, Jan., 1938
      - At Vassar College, Poughkeepsie, N.Y., in defense of capitalism, May 23, 1940
    - Articles
      - Against conscription, 1917
      - Armed neutrality, 1917
      - “Captain Hoover: Afloat in a Sieve,” 1932 (Box 134)
      - “Death and Taxes,” 1918
      - “For Positive Policies,” 1933
      - “George Record,” Nov., 1933
      - “Hoover and Power,” 1931
      - “Hoover and the Big Lift,” 1928
      - “I'm Against Union Now,” 1941
      - In Lincoln's style (unfinished), Feb., 1941
      - Keep out of war, 1917
      - Miscellaneous, 1917-1939, (4 folders)
      - “New Patriotism for Old,” 1916-1919 (Box 135)
      - “Panic of 1929,” 1928-1930, (2 folders)
      - Polity, 1933 (Box 136)
      - “Relief: 1931 Style”
      - “The Sanity of the Law,” background material, 1905-1929, (3 folders)
      - Corcoran, Thomas G., 1939
      - “Two Revolts against Oligarchy,” 1910
      - Union Now, 1934-1941
      - Wagner Health Bill, 1939
      - Walter Lippman, 1933 (Box 137)
      - “Why People Freeze,” 1918
      - “Why Trout Have Red Spots,” fable, 1939
    - Miscellaneous
      - Lists
        - Letters received and subjects, 1935-1942
        - Letters regarding Pinchot's open letters, undated
        - Letters to Franklin D. Roosevelt, 1937-1941
        - Subjects for letters, 1942
      - Unfinished letter, undated
    - Notebooks, diaries, papers and photographs, 1897-1944, undated, (1 folder) (Box 138)
    - Notes
      - How to balance the federal budget, 1937
      - Black, Hugo, and the Ku Klux Klan, 1937-1940
      - Coffin flags, 1940
      - Roosevelt, Franklin D., and Wendell L. Wilkie, 1940
      - May Bill, 1938 (Box 139)
      - Miscellaneous, 1930, undated
      - “New Notes,” 1921-1926
      - Proposed book on concentration of wealth, 1914-1937, undated
      - Unfinished articles, 1912, 1921-1923, undated (Box 140)
    - Play, “General Goober at the Battle of Anacostia,” 1932
    - Remarks
      - International tie-up, July, 1941
      - Lippman, Walter, and the war debt, 1931-1933
      - Roosevelt, Franklin D., 1941, (2 folders)
    - Review of The Public Pays by Ernest Gruening, 1932
    - Book, militarism and pacifism, unpublished, 1921, undated
  - Notebooks (Box 141)
    - Ballinger, Richard A., case, 1928
    - Progress Campaign of 1912, (2 folders)
    - Roosevelt, Theodore (1858-1919) 1927-1928, (2 folders)
    - Economics, 1928 (Box 142)
    - Introductory chapter, 1928-1936
    - Quotations, 1917, undated
    - Reconstruction, 1927-1930
    - Progressive Party, 1912, (2 folders) (Box 143)
    - Oil
      - 1931-1934, (3 folders)
      - 1935-1936, (3 folders) (Box 144)
    - Steel, 1930-1936, (2 folders)
    - Miscellaneous, 1930-1936
  - Printed articles and speeches (Box 145)
    - Set A, circa 1910-circa 1920
      - B-N, (36 folders)
      - P-W, (30 folders) (Box 146)
      - W, (26 folders) (Box 147)
    - Set B, circa 1917-circa 1929 (Box 148)
      - C-N, (24 folders)
      - R-Y, (12 folders) (Box 149)
    - Set C, circa 1915-circa 1941
      - B-E, (13 folders)
      - F-L, (27 folders) (Box 150)
      - L-R, (32 folders) (Box 151)
      - R-W, (25 folders) (Box 152)
- Printed Matter, 1910-1945 (Box 153-170)
  Newspaper clippings, articles, and other printed material. Organized in four sets.
  Arranged mainly by topic.
  - Set A, newspaper clippings (Box 153)
    - A-E, 1937-1942, (18 folders)
    - F-I, free speech clippings, 1937-1942, (17 folders) (Box 154)
    - J-P, 1935-1942, (25 folders) (Box 155)
    - P-R, Franklin D. Roosevelt speeches, 1935-1942, (14 folders) (Box 156)
    - S-W, spending, Union Now, Thomas A. Walsh, and war powers, 1934-1942, (21 folders) (Box 157)
  - Set B, peace and war clippings and articles (Box 158)
    - Miscellaneous, 1939-1942, (4 folders)
    - Joseph P. Kennedy, Charles Lindbergh, and miscellaneous, 1910, 1939-1942, (4 folders) (Box 159)
  - Set C (Box 160)
    - Public ownership, Yale University, New Haven, Conn., and miscellaneous, 1915-1936, (6 folders)
    - Miscellaneous (Box 161)
      - 1913-1925, (3 folders)
      - 1912-1942, (4 folders) (Box 162)
      - 1910-1942, (3 folders) (Box 163)
      - 1914-1938, (3 folders) (Box 164)
      - 1915-1942, (3 folders) (Box 165)
      - 1917-1941, (4 folders) (Box 166)
      - 1915-1928, (3 folders) (Box 167)
    - Miscellaneous and San Francisco Conference, 1917-1945, (3 folders) (Box 168)
    - Miscellaneous and trade, 1921-1939, (3 folders) (Box 169)
    - Miscellaneous and penal codes, 1925-1943, (3 folders) (Box 170)
  - Set D, scrapbooks See Oversize
- Oversize, 1916-1941 (Box OV 1-OV 12)
  A broadside and scrapbooks of newspaper clippings.
  Arranged and described according to the series, containers, and folders from which the items were removed.
  - Subject file (Box OV 1)
    - America Committee on War Finance
      - Broadside, 1917 (Container 74)
  - Miscellaneous printed matter (Box OV 2)
    - Set D, scrapbooks (Container 170)
      - Wilson, Woodrow, 1916
      - Mexico, 1926 (Box OV 3)
      - Roosevelt, Franklin D., and William Edgar Borah, 1935 (Box OV 4)
      - New Deal and Alfred M. Landon, 1936 (Box OV 5)
      - Miscellaneous, child labor, and speeches, 1937 (Box OV 6)
      - Roosevelt, Franklin D. (Box OV 7)
        - 1937, third term
        - 1938 (Box OV 8)
        - 1940 (Box OV 9)
        - 1941 (Box OV 10)
        - 1941, deception to enter war (Box OV 11)
        - 1941, Nazis, and war talk (Box OV 12)